The Add Force function is a function
AddForce 関数は
that's used to start a physics object moving,
物理オブジェクトの移動、
or to change the speed or direction
さらには動作のスピードや方向の変更を
of it's movement.
開始するのに使用されます。
The function has one required parameter
関数には必須パラメータがひとつだけあり、
and one optional parameter. The first
必須でないパラメータがひとつあります。
parameter is a vector that represents
最初のパラメータは、
a direction and magnitude of the force
適用したい力の方向と大きさを表すベクトルです。
to be applied. In this example
このサンプルでは
we're using minus transform.forward.
Transform.forward にマイナス記号をつけて使用します。
Remember that transform.forward is a
Transform.forward がオブジェクトの
shortcut to the Z axis in local space
ローカル空間での Z 軸のショートカットであることを
of the object.
覚えるべきです。
We're using the minus symbol here to use the inverse of
ここでマイナス記号を使用して、元の方向と逆にしています。
that direction. We're then multiplying this
次にこれに 500 を掛け算します。
by 500. This example uses a MouseDown
このサンプルでは MouseDown 関数を
function for the object and when we click
オブジェクトに使用して、オブジェクトをクリックするとき
on the object, in addition to the added force
追加した力に加えて、
we're enabling gravity on the object.
オブジェクトの重力を有効にします。
Let's see what this does.
これがどうなるか見てみます。
This script is applied to the door
このスクリプトは
in the centre of our blast door prop
blastDoor の中心にあるドアにアタッチされて、
and when I click - a force is applied
これをクリックすると、力が逆方向に
in the inverse direction.
与えられます。
Because I'm using the MouseDown function
MouseDown 関数を使用しているため、
this force is only applied once.
この力は一回のみ適用されます。
But add force can also be used in fixed
しかし AddForce は FixedUpdate で使用して
update to apply a constant force.
一定の力を適用することができます。
The second parameter is the mode of
二つめの引数は使用される力の
force being used.
モードです。
If this is left out it will default
もし引数を指定しない場合、
to the type Force.
Force 型のデフォルトが使用されます。
This is used for continuous changes
これは重さにより影響される継続的な変動に
that are effected by mass.
使用されます。
Acceleration is for continuous changes
Acceleration は重さにより影響されない
that aren't effected by mass.
継続的な変更で使用します。
Impulse is for an instant change that is
Impluse は、重さに影響される瞬間的な変動であり、
effected by mass and Velocity Change
Velocity Change は
is for an instant change that is not
重力に影響を受けない瞬間的な力で
effected by mass.
使用されます。
You should also keep in mind that forces
頭にいれておくべきこととして、
are dampened by the rigidbody's
力は Rigidbody の
drag property, for example,
Drag プロパティにより弱められ、例えば
if drag is increased,
もし Drag を増加させると
then the force applied will be less effective.
適用される力はより弱くなります。
And naturally on the opposing side
そして、反対に
if the amount of force is increased
力の量を増加させると
then the force will be more effective.
力はより大きなものになります。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)